There's a psychological trick
that I've been using to grow my following
to over
four million followers,
and to grow my revenue into the multiple
seven figures.
And using this technique can get your
audience to either love you or hate you,
and
both of those are really good for
business, and I'll explain why.
I think that so many people neglecting
this area is why they struggle to
grow online, get new followers,
and get that emotive response
that you need from
people watching your content to get them
to do business with you.
So I'm going to share this trick with you
and show you exactly how you can
implement it and apply it to your
business.
Let's begin with the enemy effect.
Let's go onto YouTube, for example.
If we go to my most popular videos,
the very first most popular video is
"Logan Paul's Most Profitable Scam Yet."
Now, there are two things working in
unison here. The first is
that I have an enemy.
By taking Logan Paul
and putting scam in there, there's beef,
as we call it in
British. Do Americans call it beef?
I don't know.
And funnily, Logan Paul
was actually a master of this.
You think that his original beef
was between him and KSI,
and I'm pretty sure if
you look back that they said that
if you really wanted to get people's
attention,
fight, because in school,
if you really wanted everyone to look at
one thing, you'd
do a fight in the playground.
No one would be able to not watch.
Then they go into business,
start their own drink.
And actually, just quickly, I suppose,
while we're on a tangent,
the thumbnail for
this.
Every thumbnail here needs to have a hero.
As you'll notice, I'm blurred
and the Prime bottle isn't because the
video's about
Prime. Prime is the hero in that,
I am not. Same with the gummies video.
It is intentional that I'm blurred.
I'm actually pretty sure that in
that gummies video, that's two photos.
Photo of the gummies, photo of me.
Then I've done something called a Gaussian
blur
on myself to take it out because I'd much
rather you looked at the gummies, not me.
And we'll get onto this in a little second
to the significance of that.
The next thing I've done here
is I've gone for a visual hook.
Rather than just taking his video
and showing it, I was like,
imagine a world where
my videographer shows me that,
and then I have to do a reaction.
It's kind of when people watch the
introduction, they know what's coming.
This 20-ounce bottle of Gatorade has 34
grams of sugar in it.
One bottle of Prime has two grams.
Frustrated sigh, get in the car.
Again, little bit of misdirection.
What's happening here? Get in the car.
[upbeat music] This guy has no idea.
Logan Paul,
you're trying to make your drink the most
popular rehydration drink in
the world. So these guys have signed-
Straight away, you can tell
that I've got a
problem with Logan Paul.
I've got a problem with the drink.
I'm being a contrarian.
Where so many people at this point two
years ago were sucking it off as being the
best thing since sliced bread,
I needed an enemy.
Now, for some of you that don't know,
this video has been done before
by me. Here we go. "Why Prime
Is Garbage For Rehydration."
So if you look, fuck,
that still did over 200,000 views.
But let's look into this one. Cool.
500 pound, couple thousand subscribers.
But you'll notice here,
I tried to make the enemy Prime, not Logan
Paul. And now when we get
that kind of emotive response towards an
enemy, hating a
product is one thing,
but hating a person
is always just going to get a little bit
more. And for the record,
I don't hate Logan Paul.
I actually find some of the stuff he's
done very impressive.
So if we start looking at this one.
If there's one thing you should know about
me,
I'm a sweater.
Surprised I'm not rocking a Patches
O'Houlihan right now.
All I need is this-
Should've treated this audio with AI,
but I'm pretty sure it's
over two years ago. Didn't yet.
I didn't know what I was doing.
Sniff of a warmup or a brisk jog,
and I'm sweating more than when the missus
messages you saying,
"We need to talk." So
if you're someone like me, that when you
get your heart rate above 75 beats per
minute, you're sweating more than a
pregnant-
So you see I took a little bit too long
getting into this, didn't I?
This is when I was still editing
everything myself.
I didn't even allude to the fact
that it...
I tried making this too much about me.
But anyway,
so this video had already been done,
but it just didn't do well enough,
so I made it again,
but I made it with a different enemy in
mind, Logan.
Now, this video was done before this,
and that video was called "Are
Electrolytes Worth the Hype?" So the
original video that this came from, I
went to jujitsu. I've got my water bottle.
Put it out on the side. It's yellow.
Someone goes, "What's in that?" I went,
"Electrolytes." They go, "What do you need
that for?" I was like,
"What do you mean what do I need it for?"
I was like, "We're
losing salt whilst training.
We're training for over 90 minutes."
And then I
realized that I make a good educational
video.
But then when I put
that video onto YouTube, no one cared.
So then I tried thinking, okay, what
is a popular hydration drink that's in gen
pop? Prime. Tried that.
200,000 people cared.
Bring Logan Paul into the fray as a common
enemy.
Go head-to-head with him for the beef.
Most viewed video ever.
Now, the creatine gummies scandal.
We have an enemy, and that enemy for
that is businesses that do not put
any creatine in their gummies.
Here we have another enemy,
the downfall of modern
podcasts. Now, it's worth noting here
that I've changed the hero for this
is going
to be the three of those. Now,
considering I'm not in this thumbnail
and I've gone
with some very, very popular characters,
what we need to do, and this isn't spoken
about enough,
is we need to pay off the packaging.
So on YouTube,
you have to pay off the packaging with
your introduction.
You don't quite have to do this in
short-form content.
So if we start watching this,
you realize I have to make people feel
well aware
what's happening so early on.
I'm sure you've realized ever since the
pandemic that
absolutely everyone you've ever met has
now got a podcast.
And this,
it's not even plugged into anything.
But there is a big problem on the horizon
that we're already starting to
experience. Nice little J cut there.
Follow me.
Now you're probably like, "What
were you filming then?"
Is it too much to ask?
That wasn't fake, by the way. That
was genuinely
SEM being a retard. Keep the camera on me.
Now, problem number one is
if you're like me,
I like listening to the Joe Rogan
Podcast. So we get into something here,
and we point out the common enemy being
that podcasts are a business. They
are not just people having a conversation.
I managed to go through that
and break down exactly why people would
have people on
that say things that are conflicting.
I'm pretty sure I saw one this morning.
Thrive CEO. Coffee for breakfast
is destroying your hormones.
Is it? Is it? Fucking doubt it. Anyway.
Fat-shaming Piers Morgan on live TV.
Common enemy. Although I like Piers.
He's my boy. Then we move down here,
and we have some other ones.
Now, is creatine worth the hype?
I think I was one of the first people to
pretend I was snorting it using an Amex.
Now everyone's done that. Bit rinsed.
Here we go. Is AG1 a scam? Again,
common enemy.
Here with the packaging,
you'll notice there
is a green mustache on me, but the
bag's not been opened yet.
So before I even started recording,
got as many pictures
of the bag, et cetera.
I actually saw an outlier thumbnail online
where someone had
a million views talking about AG1,
and he had the green 'tache.
So I actually stole
that from someone else. Again,
good 800,000 views.
Beautiful. Common enemy, AG1. Now,
Chris has got a bit of blowback in
the past for me going after companies
that sponsor him.
Now,
the reason I don't call Chris a grifter
is he genuinely loves AG1.
Like when you travel,
he's actually bumming it still.
But I will say this.
If that formula was so good like they said
when I did that
video, and all the rebuttals,
then why did they reformulate?
You know what I mean?
If your formula was so good,
why did you have to create a brand-new
version of
it Hmm. V Shred, common enemy.
If you put V Shred in everything, everyone
hates him.
And then we come down to the other videos
down here, where the common
enemy is not quite so prevalent.
Joe Wicks, common enemy.
And you'll find there's a layer of
inception in here.
So go after Joe Wicks quite a bit because
he's just a bit of a pleb, isn't he?
And then you'll notice he's actually in
the back of some of my videos.
I put him in there just for a bit of fun.
So whenever I put a common enemy in a
video, we get an
outlier of some kind. So how can
that apply to short-form content?
Well, first of all,
if you need help with your short-form
content, there's going to
be a link in the description to Short Form
Content Mastery.
It's pretty bloody good.
But there's also a bundle in there where
you can get
access to all the courses
that I have online for a massive discount.
For short form,
we need to start with a hook.
Now, a hook is something
that you say to make someone
and convince them to stay.
Now,
if you were to watch me in bed at night
swiping, it would look like this.
I'm not really giving many people more
than a few seconds, so we need to
hook them. We go from a hook to a setup.
We go from a setup to a payoff.
Now,
the hooks we have can be several things.
Question.
Let's pretend the creatine gummies scandal
is something people are making content
about. So the question could be,
why do creatine gummies so often not have
creatine
in them? Then everyone
that wants the answer stays.
All the people that don't care leave.
Now,
if you can create a question well enough
that most people want to stay, you've
done well. We have a statement hook.
Creatine gummies are a scam. This is why.
We could have a preview hook where I could
show a later part of the video and be
like,
"I cannot believe that's the amount of
creatine in them." Then we go back to
the introduction.
So there's loads of different ways to do
hooks, but very good
ways to do hooks are to have an enemy
hook.
Now,
some people do this by reacting to
content, and then that visual you get of
that person from their video. And
if you are going to download that video,
you can
do it on SnapTik, InstaDownload.
You go into... I'll show you now,
actually.
This isn't legal, by the way.
If you wanted to get a TikTok thing,
go to SnapTik.
Then you paste the URL there, apparently,
and you will get the video to download.
So then you have a visual hook of you
reacting to that content as an enemy.
And then most people, I would say this,
instead of just sitting there watching
the video like this,
it looks like you're cucking a fucking
video third party.
So for any of you out there doing that,
I would recommend that you do some kind of
hook like,
"You're not going to believe this." Show
their video, then do the
response.
Don't leave their video on screen for too
long because people just get
bored. They're like,
"Get on with it." So having an enemy also
could be an amazing
part of having a hook, because in
that hook, you're like,
"This person's wrong.
I'm going to explain why."
Or you say things like, "This person
is chatting shit
again," like this video. Joe Wicks and I,
we go way back.
Welcome back to The Body Coach TV. That
is a hook that I am
using. Well,
it's actually an introduction,
but to have a common enemy.
And then what was the other one I did
here?
What's the first thing I say in this?
Joe Wicks is back chatting absolute shit
again, but this time...
People love the beef.
People love the common enemy.
So when it comes to identifying who would
make a good enemy, think about this.
First thing, so many flipping people,
let's say personal trainers, because I
come from a background of personal
training.
So many personal trainers
are worried about posting content based
upon the fact
that other personal trainers
are going to judge them.
I'm like,
"Why would you care about what personal
trainers think?
They're the only people
that will never buy your stuff." So
actually, if you've got
a cohort of people that
are never going to buy your stuff,
they are the perfect
people to go after to be a common enemy.
Think about this.
I've always gone after vegans.
I've always gone after people on keto
diets.
I've always gone after people
that run because they're never going to
buy my stuff.
They're the perfect common enemy.
Joe Wicks fans love burpees,
love their front room, and love coconut
oil.
They are not going to be the right people
for my program. Great common enemy.
Vegan people, too ideologically captured.
The vegans, there's some good ones,
but most of them, the last
few years, love putting a flag in the bio,
Ukraine, Palestine.
Then when people start putting the St
George's flag up, they're like, "Get the
flags down." Then keto people.
Some people call them ketards.
I don't think that's an appropriate thing
to do.
Make a common enemy. So over the years,
I used to attack other personal trainers.
Another thing that I used to go after
is bodybuilders because bodybuilders are
never going to buy my stuff.
So you can call them stupid,
call them insecure.
Take the piss out of the fact, oh,
you spent 30 weeks getting
lean enough that you could put some fake
tan on and impress other people.
I'm not saying bodybuilding's gay.
But I'm saying if you're a dude starving
yourself for three months to get a load of
fake tan on to impress another guy on a
judging panel, it's a bit gay.
Perfect common enemy. So
if you're making content in your niche,
start by saying that other people
are wrong. Start by being a contrarian.
Start by going against the grain.
Some of the best books in history
are all about
going against a principle
that people stand for and believe in.
Which brings me onto my next point
that I think is really important for
people, is
that sometimes you need to polarize an
audience.
And I put this in one of my books.
Say you're going to someone's family
barbecue.
If you agree with everyone
and you're just vanilla,
no one's going to remember you.
But rather, someone talks about Formula 1,
you go, "Look, I'm not being funny, I
think Formula 1's shit." Six out of ten
people are going to go, "Who the fuck's
this guy?" Four out of ten people
are going to go, "What
was your name again?"
"James." "Have a beer,
because I also think
that Formula 1's shit as well.
Have a seat." And so many people
are trying to have a fucking popularity
contest,
trying to suck each other off.
But being popular doesn't pay the bills.
Like Eddie Hall,
he's got way more followers than me,
and he's broke, allegedly.
Oh, his views really dropped off,
didn't they?
Whoever's doing their thumbnails,
not good, bruv. It's not good.
He was a flash in the pan. This
is why I felt sorry for him.
I genuinely felt sorry for him because he
was getting all this
attention, media hype, and I knew this
was the way he was going.
So today I'm going to be reacting to a
video, like a mini documentary, on how
Coca-Cola is actually killing Mexico.
Let's go.
So for those of you that
are thinking about building a cult-like
audience,
it's a very good idea to select some
enemies.
But now I'm not saying go out there
and burn bridges with people for the sake
of
it. I'm saying be strategic.
Think about a cohort of people that
are never going to
do business with you.
Think about some contrarian points
that you could go to war
with,
and think about things where people have
got common beliefs or misconceptions
that they're wrong about. Now,
you can have an enemy as a principle,
whether it's
fasted cardio,
whether it's a low-carb diet,
whether it is something financial
like where you invest your money, ISAs,
ETFs.
Let's have a look at Damien Talks Money.
Let's see if he's got any common enemies.
The common enemy here would be people
that say to invest instead of paying off
your
mortgage. Actually, a lot of his,
he's not too contrarian about.
Let's have a look at someone else maybe.
Mike Israetel. This would be pretty easy.
Common enemy. Sugar is the enemy. Look,
his most viewed video has the word enemy
in
it. That's what I mean. Second one,
scammer, enemy.
Stop wasting money, where the enemy
is supplement companies trying to take you
for
all the money you've got.
Common enemy here, David Goggins.
So you'll see,
you may not have just seen it before.
Think about Jake Paul.
Think about how high he's climbed over the
last few years, because he makes an
enemy out of every single opponent,
then he quite literally fights them.
It is all cleverly rehearsed. Beef, drama.
What else have we got here? Cor,
when did I subscribe to some of these?
Courtney Black.
Why am I subscribed to that? Cor,
lockdown must've been tough, eh?
Logan Paul's most viewed video,
beef with his brother.
Next one, diss track, fall of Jake Paul.
So you'll start to appreciate now
that having a common enemy is the most
important way to build a cult-like
persona, because there
are billions of people in
the world, and all you need
is a few thousand of them
that strongly agree with your
mission, your values. And this
is my best bit of advice
that I'll close off with.
Instead of trying to get people to love
you, instead pick a small percentage of
people that you want to dislike you.
It is impossible to be liked with
everyone, so don't try.
It is a very poor tactic to use.
So in your next few videos, think of an
enemy. Is it a product?
Is it a way people are wasting resources?
Is it a person? Is it an arch nemesis?
Is it a peer?
Is it a principle? Whatever it is,
start your hook and your setup
going to war with that
and watch it perform better than
everything else.
Hope you enjoyed this video.
If you enjoyed this,
you'll probably love this one
right here. So give that one a watch.